Make sure you eat it all up!
Wh-What is this?
Delicious ukogi leaves.
No, that's not what I meant.
There's more if you want.
The hedge?!
If we eat the whole hedge,
I'll be able to see straight into the next building!
What if the wife and daughter there are changing?!
Next door is my house.
I see.
Here you go.
How did things get so bad that
I'm reduced to eating leaves?
Wait. They're actually good.
Eat them and you're sure
to get a promotion!
The recipe's been passed down in these barracks for generations!
In other words, "If you want
real food, get a promotion"?
But you know...
Unless you start eating food with more nutrients, you'll never grow.
You saw Katsuie's rack, right?
She gets to eat delicious food
because she's Nobuna's minister,
and so she's got those jiggly melons.
Breasts are just for decoration!
Oh! We were just talking
about your breasts—
Monkey, please come with me.
Oda Nobuna no Yabou
The moment you swing the sword you pledged upon
You get hurt again
Biting down on my lip
I try to figure out what the right thing is
I will protect you, but before that
There's something I must do
I'm not trying to stand out
I just don't want to be a liar
I live on the battlefield with my life on the line
Whenever I look back, you're there to reassure me
The days of sorrow end, and the sun of ambition rises
Let's defeat fate and go as far as we want
Linking the world
Episode Two
Oda Clan
Power Struggles
Episode Two
Oda Clan
Power Struggles
Episode Two
Oda Clan
Power Struggles
Episode Two
Oda Clan
Power Struggles
In Owari Province, a new market system has
allowed people the right to trade freely,
bringing more prosperity than the people have ever known.
Inuchiyo, why are you following us?
I can't?
I suppose you can.
Are you two having a tryst?
D-Don't be stupid!
Inuchiyo, go home.
It's time for us adults to have fun.
Fun with fat?
Boobs aren't fat!
They're filled with men's hopes and dreams!
How uncouth.
I thought I'd take a look at my sister's monkey.
I didn't think I'd see this.
Oda
Nobukatsu
Oda Kanjuurou Nobukatsu.
Oda
Nobukatsu
If Nobuna hadn't been born, he would have become head of the Oda Clan.
Oda
Nobukatsu
In our history, Nobunaga's little brother...
But maybe a monkey is a good match
for my stupid and boorish sister.
So you're calling your
older sister a fool?
You're the one who's a boor!
Monkey, hold your tongue.
He's insulting Nobuna!
I'm a minister of the Oda family,
but my official position
is Master Nobukatsu's aide.
I'm in his command.
You don't know anything, do you?
Like what my sister did at Father's funeral...
She just had to put on
that stupid tough act.
If I leave the country to her,
Owari will be ruined.
Then, what about you?
What would you do with Owari?
Do you have some ambition
for the country?
I'll use a national campaign to get everyone to eat rice jelly!
Disqualified!
You're not worthy of being a count!
The best you could be is
the governor of a prefecture!
I take it back!
I'll destroy the Imagawa and Saitou!
And then...
I'll bring all the cute girls to Owari!
Me and him might actually get along, but...
That's still no good!
If you could be a count,
then even I could!
A-Anyway, my sister is a fool.
An embarrassment to the Oda clan!
Even Mother hated her since she
was a child, never speaking to her.
Violent, selfish, and always
friendly with barbarians...
All she talked about was rifles and conquest.
I can see why my mother didn't like her.
My mother said that I should've been the one to succeed my father, not my foolish sister.
Ouch!
Monkey!
Never call your sister a fool again.
Next time you say that,
I'll really whack you!
You hit me! You've already hit me!
You're just a mere soldier!
I'll have your head! Off with his head!
Do you realize what you've done?
Master Nobukatsu ordered me to cut off
Monkey's head and deliver it to him.
Ah, right.
If you refuse, he'll start
another rebellion.
He always does.
Ah, right.
So we'll give him Yoshiharu's head?
Ah—As if we would!
But rebellion would be a problem.
If the Oda family is divided in two...
Don't lecture me!
Whose fault do you think this is?!
If Master Nobukatsu rebels,
then I'll have to fight Lord Nobuna.
The only option here is to cut off Monkey's head!
Put your sword away!
Calm down, Katsuie.
If a foot soldier hits him,
that's clearly unacceptable.
But if he were higher ranked,
a general for instance,
then couldn't we work something out?
From foot soldier to
general in one step, huh?
However, he'd have to earn that title.
3000 kan...
Use 3000 kan to bring me 8000
koku worth of rice in one week.
But at Owari's market prices,
he'd only be able to buy 4000 koku.
If he can't do that,
he doesn't deserve it.
So, you want me to get as much rice
as I can at half the market rate.
Okay!
Scripted event time!
If you can't do it in a week,
you're going to lose your head.
Don't worry.
I have a way to make money that
never failed me in the game.
Game?
I don't understand that either.
Well, just leave it to me.
I'm told you need lots of rice.
The Kawanami ninjas
were originally thieves.
Breaking and entering is a
sim... simple task for us.
Don't stutter when you're talking
about doing something illegal.
You don't need to do
anything like that. I'm fine.
But it's 8000 koku!
I just need to increase
my 3000 kan to 6000 kan.
Yoshiharu
Sagara
Kan
Owari Province
Town of
Kiyosu
First, I need to use all my money
to buy goods here in Kiyosu.
Town of
Kiyosu
Inoguchi
Town of
Kiyosu
Inoguchi
I'll take them to a town
where they're worth more,
Town of
Kiyosu
Inoguchi
Town of
Kiyosu
Inoguchi
Town of
Kiyosu
Inoguchi
Town of
Kiyosu
Inoguchi
Town of
Kiyosu
Inoguchi
Town of
Kiyosu
Inoguchi
Town of
Kiyosu
Inoguchi
Town of
Kiyosu
Inoguchi
Town of
Kiyosu
Inoguchi
Town of
Kiyosu
Inoguchi
Town of
Kiyosu
Inoguchi
Town of
Kiyosu
Inoguchi
Town of
sell them there, buy more goods,
take them to another
Town of
Inoguchi
town and sell them for more again.
Town of
Inoguchi
If I keep doing this, making 6000
kan won't take any time at all!
I learned this trick in Romance of the
Two Kingdoms and Age of Exploration!
His failure's all but decided.
I can't wait a week!
This is your chance.
If Lord Nobuna doesn't give you
his head after the week is up,
you have the perfect excuse to rebel.
Okay.
You need to make the tea more calmly.
It's fine.
It's all the same when
it's in your stomach.
Anyway, how's Monkey doing?
Are you worried?
I-I'm just asking!
What about Nobukatsu?
He's preparing for war.
Will you forgive him again?
I'll kill him.
He's your flesh and blood.
If I can't unite my own house,
then Japan is beyond me.
No matter how much Mother begs,
I'm not giving him another chance.
Fifty points.
With this much money,
the ladies will flock to me!
You're so greedy.
I'm disappointed in you, Monkey!
Say what you like!
Money is power!
You have money,
but not a single grain of rice.
I got so obsessed with making money
that I forgot my original goal!
When's the deadline?!
This evening.
Crap.
You stupid monkey!
Why isn't there any rice?
Where's the money I gave you?
Did you blow it on gambling?
No! No!
I actually increased it!
How?
Trade secret.
You're using Monkey Language to trick me!
Inuchiyo and the others are buying the
rice and bringing it here right now!
It's true!
I see.
If you're that sure,
I'll wait until evening.
They're late.
I'm tired of waiting.
You just sat down!
Just how impatient are you?
But waiting is boring.
When I'm bored, I feel like killing monkeys.
Let's talk to kill time, instead.
Sure.
Okay. I'll use this globe
to judge your intelligence.
Interesting.
I'll take your challenge.
Do you understand what this globe means?
The world's not flat.
Just like this, it's round.
I know that.
Huh? You're lying.
It's common knowledge in my world.
Then do you know where Japan is?
This tiny island country, I'm told.
The people you call "barbarians" come from all the way over here, in Europe.
Spain and Portugal...
Amazing.
Nobody I've explained this
to has ever believed me.
The barbarians will
invade Japan someday.
We need to make a country that can
stand up to them as soon as possible.
Is what I'm saying strange?
Do you think I'm a fool?
No.
You're just too much of a genius.
The people who laugh at you
don't understand that.
Oda Nobuna, you're special.
Don't worry about it.
You say the same thing, huh?
As who?
Someone I care about deeply.
The person who told me about the world.
The person you care about?
Who is it? Damn it.
Jealous? Could you be jealous?
N-No!
Sure about that?
Damn. I wouldn't fall for
a brat like you, anyway.
You're a lord, and I only
carry your shoes.
No one can make that
big a jump in status.
What's that look on your face?
What are you thinking?
N-Nothing much!
Liar.
That's not like you.
Are you plotting rebellion or something?
Not exactly rebellion.
More like conquest.
Conquest of what, exactly?
Well... Um...
What?
It's sunset.
Time's up.
I'm cutting off your head, Monkey.
I'm sorry, Monkey.
But I'm the countess of Owari Province.
I cannot let my personal feelings interfere.
If I don't give you my head,
Nobukatsu will rebel.
That has to be avoided at all costs.
Any last words?
Nope.
Of course you do!
"I don't want to die!"
or "Don't kill me!"
Don't be silly.
If I beg for my life,
it'll make this harder for you.
You...
don't like this stuff at all, do you?
Shut up!
It's not worth letting an idiot like you live.
That's right.
I'm only doing this because you told me to.
It's your own fault!
Princess, no!
Inuchiyo! Goemon!
I'm sorry.
We were interrupted on the
way and time ran out.
The rice is being brought in now.
There's so much.
How much is there?
30,000 koku.
30,000 koku?!
That's almost four times
what I asked for!
Sagara succeeded.
What a relief.
Thank goodness.
Be happy, Monkey.
As a result of your success,
you may keep your head.
So I got a reprieve, huh?
But this success belongs to
these two for their hard work.
And be very grateful for my compassion.
What?
You're so not cute.
Princess!
Disaster.
Master Nobukatsu has rebelled.
He's raised an army at Suemori Castle!
Wh-Why?
It was Master Nobukatsu's forces who tried to stop us.
Since they failed, he decided to raise an army.
It can't be.
Sakuma Nobunori and Hayashi Michikatsu
have barricaded themselves inside the castle with Master Nobukatsu.
As has Katsuie.
Please reconsider!
You are Master Nobukatsu's
advisor, Katsuie.
Now is the time to show your loyalty.
B-But...
We'll attack Suemori Castle.
Wait!
Calm down!
Master Nobukatsu is merely being prompted by Sakuma and Hayashi.
I know that!
Then...
We can't have a power struggle right now!
As soon as the Imagawa learn of this, they'll attack.
We capture Suemori Castle.
That's our only hope.
At this rate...
she'll kill her brother,
just like in the game.
Once you capture Suemori Castle...
Nobukatsu just has to surrender, right?
The next morning, 1200 of Nobuna's
men surrounded Suemori Castle.
C-Can we really beat my sister?
We have the fierce general
Shibata Katsuie with us.
If she's prepared to sacrifice her life to do so,
she'll be able to slay the foolish princess.
W-We don't have to kill her.
Nobuna! Nobuna! Nobuna!
What's going on?
Nobuna! Shout even louder!
Let everyone in that castle know
that our leader is Oda Nobuna!
Can we really win like this?
Master Nobukatsu is very weak-willed.
We simply need to make him loose his will to fight.
It's a splendid plan!
Eighty-two points.
But this is kind of embarrassing.
What do we do?
I don't want to fight the princess.
Lord Nobuna...
Nobuna! Nobuna! Nobuna!
Do something about that yelling!
Nobuna!
It's over!
Traitor!
Surrender.
I surrender!
By not restraining Master Nobukatsu, I have failed as a minister.
Please take my life and forgive him.
If I lose you, how am I supposed to fight the Imagawa?
I refuse.
Then, you'll spare Master Nobukatsu?
Nobukatsu commits seppuku.
That'll really hurt!
I don't want to die like that!
I can't, Sister!
I see.
Then I'll kill you myself.
Stop it, Nobuna!
I told you.
A count can't let their personal
feelings get in the way.
Everyone, listen to me.
From now on, anyone who goes against me,
family or not, will be killed.
For the sake of our conquest.
For the sake of the people!
Nobody has a problem with that, do they?
Sister...
Goodbye,
Kanjuurou.
Wait!
Nobuna, don't kill your brother!
You're going to go against me?!
Yeah, I am!
If you kill him here,
you're going to go on killing
everyone you care about.
You're going to end up a monster!
If I let him go because he's a relative of mine,
then how can I set an
example to everyone else?
Listen to me.
I've known the life of a count,
much like you, very well.
Ever since he killed his
rebellious younger brother,
it destroyed a part of his
heart, and he lost control.
I don't want you to end up like him!
I want you to stay the girl who spins
a globe and talks about her dreams!
Then what do you want me to do?!
Be honest with yourself!
What do you really want to do with him?!
I don't want to kill him!
Does any girl want to kill her little brother?
That's all you had to say.
Fine.
I'll forgive Nobukatsu.
I'll be reborn and work for you, my sister!
I'll never start another rebellion.
I will abandon the name of Oda,
take the name of our Tsuda relatives,
and henceforth be called Tsuda Nobusumi!
Tsuda Nobusumi, huh?
The rest of the rebels were also forgiven,
and swore their loyalty to Nobuna.
Thus, Owari was united under Oda Nobuna.
In your future, the moon still shines like this, right?
Pretty much.
So, you finally believe
I'm from the future?
That person who killed his brother...
really existed, right?
In the future I know.
But I don't know your future.
Even if you did,
I'd kill you if you told me.
Harsh.
I don't want to think that
I'm being controlled by you.
Promise me.
Got it.
But if I can see that you're going
to lose sight of your own path,
I'll do something about it.
Okay?
That's fine.
Then you can swear an oath of loyalty.
An oath?
The barbarian way is much
cooler, and more elegant.
Kiss my hand.
This is how a knight swears
loyalty to a princess.
Oh, well.
Sagara Yoshiharu.
Swear that I will be your lord,
and your loyalty will never die.
Sure.
Will you swear eternal loyalty to me?
Until I find a way back to my time.
All right. Until then.
Yeah. I'll never betray you.
I'll make your dream come true.
Then if my dream never comes true,
you won't ever leave.
Maybe.
Yoshiharu, swear to me.
tada jidai no mannaka tatasarete tomadou toki ni
When I, lost in time, was standing there confused
te wo hiite kureta hito e dekiru koto sagashita
You pulled me through, so I wanted to do something in return
kizutsuki nagara warau sugata
You were smiling even though you were being hurt
kokoro no ura namida ga mieta
I saw you shedding tears deep inside
sukui motomeru koe kikitoreru no wa
I could only understand your call for help
yurusareta mono dake
When you opened up to me
kazoe kirenu arashi wo koete
I will overcome the countless storms
anata no yami sabaku hikari ni naru
And become the light that dispels your darkness
mou mayowanai tomo ni ikitai
I won't hesitate anymore; let's go together
chikau yume ga donna mubou de atte mo
No matter how unrealistic our ambitions are
oboeteite shinjirareru basho wa
Remember there's a place you can believe in
koko ni aru to
Right here
Episode Three
The Mino
Disturbance
Episode Three
The Mino
Disturbance
Episode Three
The Mino
Disturbance
Episode Three
The Mino
Disturbance